Gnome Press Records
Gnome Press Records
1948-1952
Gnome Press.
0.5 linear ft.
Papers of the Gnome Press, founded in 1948 by Martin Greenberg and David Kyle. Includes correspondence, production material, and publicity.
149007
Biographical History
Gnome Press was founded in 1948 by Martin Greenberg and David Kyle. It intended to specialize in light space opera and whimsical fantasy but ended up publishing blood-and-thunder fantasy and minor works by major authors. Eighty-six titles were published, the last in 1962.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Gnome Press Records consist of correspondence, one subject file, production material, publicity material, and published material. Correspondence contains incoming and outgoing correspondence, arranged together chronologically. Subject files consists of a single file of blank contract forms. Production material contains book jackets, correspondence, financial papers, and blank forms. Publicity material consists of advertising brochures. Published material contains a single book.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Science fiction; Publishing, printing and book arts; Gnome Press.; Publishers and publishing, United States.; Science fiction, American.; Correspondence.; Publishers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous, 1951-1952; undated (Box 1)
- Subject file
  - Contracts, undated (Box 1)
- Production material
  - The Sword of Conan (book), 1952; t.p., table of contents (Box 1)
  - Book jackets (proofs), undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1952; undated (Box 1)
  - Financial papers, 1951-1952; undated (Box 1)
  - Mss notes, undated (Box 1)
  - Order forms (blank) (Box 1)
  - Price lists, 1948; 1950 (Box 1)
  - Type samples, undated (Box 1)
- Publicity material
  - Advertising brochures, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Advertising brochures (proofs), 1950-1951; undated (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Travelers of Space (book), 1951 (Box 1)